#### JUAN RAMIREZ

Middleton, Wisconsin | juancra264@hotmail.com | +1 (608) 572-6995

https://juan.radutech.site/|linkedin.com/in/juancra264|github.com/juancra264/

#### ABOUT ME

IT professional with over 16 years of experience in designing, deploying, and operating IP networks and IT infrastructure solutions for large-scale enterprises. Proficient in data networking, security systems, project management, and infrastructure operations in both on-premises and cloud environments. A fast learner who adapts easily to change, with a consistent eagerness to learn and grow in the field. A devoted husband and proud father of two children.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Network Administrator Nov 2024 - Present

Emmi Roth USA | Stoughton, WI, United States

Responsible for managing, planning, renewing, and operating the network infrastructure architecture across various cheese-making locations and operational facilities. Develop and implement projects such as WAN/LAN resiliency and the NMS platform for lifecyle network operations.

### Network Technical Lead Nov 2020 - Dec 2023

Mercado Libre Colombia | Bogotá, Colombia

Responsible for planning and supporting the network infrastructure architecture for the largest e-commerce platform in Latin America. Act as the focal point and technical lead for operations in Argentina, Chile, Colombia, Mexico, and Brazil. Ensure seamless connectivity, operational continuity, and security, while defining technologies and solutions from multiple providers for both connectivity and security. Lead initiatives to integrate on-premise operations with multicloud services across all Mercado Libre regions.

#### Technology Specialist Apr 2017 - Nov 2020

BT Latam now Sencinet | Bogotá, Colombia

Manage and oversee infrastructure operations for BT Latam / Sencinet Tier III and Tier IV datacenters in Colombia, focusing on high-speed networking and colocation services. Responsible for the operation and administration of regional IT infrastructure, including firewalls, physical and virtual servers, storage systems, operating systems, and DNS services.

# Senior Network Engineer Nov 2015 - Apr 2017

RCN TV | Bogotá, Colombia

Responsible for managing IP infrastructure and operations, including networks, firewalls, physical and virtual servers, storage, and applications, to support tech-

nical TV broadcasting at RCN Television S.A., a leading broadcast company in Colombia. Oversee and execute various projects focused on high-speed switching, IT/OT systems integration, storage solutions, video broadcasting recorders, streaming services, and the implementation of virtualization for services, servers, and infrastructure.

Network Engineer Jun 2012 - Oct 2015

Fanalca S.A. | Cali, Colombia

Responsible for the deployment and administration of the data network platform (switches and routers), perimeter security (firewalls, VPN concentrators, and content inspection), and telephony systems for Fanalca S.A. and its affiliated companies.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Aruba Certified Mobility - Associate (ACMA) View credentials

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (AWS SAA) View credentials

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (AWS CPC) View credentials

Ruckus ICX Implementer Accreditation View credentials

ITILv3 Foundation View credentials

### **EDUCATION**

MSc Business for IT (MBIT) Computer Science Aug 2018 - Nov 2020

Universidad de los Andes, Bogotá (Colombia)

Electronic Engineer July 2002 - Mar 2009

Pontificia Univerdad Javeriana, Cali (Colombia)

## **SKILLS**